I really believe this is one of the best
opportunities for data scientists and AI engineers
right
now.
In this video, I will give you an introduction to
the Langchain library using Python.
Langchain is a framework for developing applications
using large language models.
I will walk you through all the modules, then the
quick start guide and then finally, we
will create our first app which will be a personal
assistant that can answer questions
about any YouTube video that you provided with.
So what is it?
It's a framework for developing applications powered
by large language models like OpenAI's
GPT models.
And instead of just interacting with these models
using an API, so basically you ask
a question, for example, this is what you do when
you interact with chat GPT, but in
the background is just an API that you send a
message to and then get the message back.
That's how you normally interact with large language
models.
So Langchain is a framework around that, that also
allows your application to become data
aware and agentic.
So data aware means that you can connect a language
model to other data sources.
So for example, your own data, company data that you
can build on and agentic means allow
a language model to interact with its environment.
So it's not just asking a question and then getting
information back, no, it's also acting
on that information by using various tools, for
example, that we will get into in a bit.
So now you want to learn a framework like Langchain
and I really want to get deep into
this because I believe there will be so many
opportunities if you understand this correctly.
So I work as a freelance data scientist and up until
this point, basically my job as a
data scientist is to help companies, usually larger
companies that have a lot of historical
data and use that to train machine learning models
on.
But what we're seeing right now with these
pre-trained large language models like OpenAI's
is that also smaller companies without huge amounts
of historical data can start to leverage
the power of AI.
And now me working as a freelancer, this provides me
with a lot of opportunities actually to
also work with smaller businesses doing smaller
project while also still being able to make
great impact for that company.
And also with really large machine learning projects
using lots of historical data, you
also never really quite know what you're going to
get.
So actually a lot of data science projects fail.
And I believe using these large language models for
small businesses or even for large businesses
will be a much more predictable way of doing AI
projects because the model is already there.
You know what it can do and now you just have to
provide it with extra information and tune
it to a specific use case.
So if you learn this, if you understand Langchain
and more specifically the underlying principles
basically of this particular framework, then I think
you will set yourself up for many
great opportunities to come.
You can really make a lot of money here if you
understand this correctly.
So let's get into this.
So I will start off by explaining all the different
modules to you, all the different
building blocks of the Langchain library that you
can use to start building your intelligent
apps.
And after briefly explaining each of the core
components, I will give you an example from
the quick start guide within VS code.
So you also have an idea of what it looks like in
code and how you can use it.
And there is also a GitHub page available for this
project that you can go to.
Link is in the description so you can clone it and
you can follow along.
Here I also explain how to set this up and what kind
of API keys you need and how to
set up the environment and install the keys in your
.env file.
So if you're not familiar with that, I would suggest
checking out this GitHub page so that
way you can follow along.
But coming back to the getting started page over
here.
So these are all the modules in increasing order of
complexity.
So we will start simple and we will start off with
the models.
So these are the model integrations that Langchain
supports.
And there is a whole list over here that you can
check out.
But you have the models from OpenAI.
You have for example Hugging Face and a whole lot of
other different models that are supported
right now.
So that is the first module.
So now let's see what it looks like in VS code.
So I have an example over here where I load the
OpenAI model from the Langchain library
and I can basically define my model by providing a
specific parameter here for the model name.
So for this example we are going to use the text
DaVinci 3 model.
If you go to the API reference for OpenAI you can
see there are a lot of models that
you can pick.
A lot of models that you can choose from.
I am currently on the waitlist for GPT-4.
So once you get access to that it will become even
better.
But coming back to the example over here.
So we load our model and then we can basically
provide it with a prompt.
So let's say write a poem about Python and AI.
So let's first initialize the model.
Then store our prompt.
And now we are going to call the model and put in
the prompt.
So it will now send out a connection to the OpenAI
API with our prompt and then it will
give us back the result.
So this is just a general way of interacting with
these large language models and something
that I can also do in chat GPT.
So here you can see the poem that we get back from
the API.
So this is nothing new up until this point.
But this is the starting point that we need in order
to interact with these language models.
Then next on the list is prompts.
And this you can use to manage your prompts,
optimize them and also serialize them.
So coming back to our project we have the prompt
template over here that we can also
import from the Lang chain library.
And the prompt template what we can do we can
provide it with an input variable and
then a template.
So what we can do with this is we can basically ask
user information or get some kind of variable
information and then put it into a prompt.
Similar to how you would use f-strings for example
in Python.
And this is just a nice class that you can use and
there are more things you can do with
it but this is just a basic example so we can
provide the prompt template over here.
Let me clear this up for you.
So what is a good name for a company that makes and
then between curly brackets product.
And then we see the input variables is product over
here and now we can call prompt.format
and then we can provide the product.
So after running this what you can see is that we
now have the prompt what is a good
name for a company that makes smart apps using large
language models.
And then the third component is memory.
So we can provide our intelligent app with both long
term and short term memory to make
smarter basically so it does not forget the previous
interaction that it has had with
the user.
So coming back to our example over here we can
import the conversation chain.
So that is also from Lang chain import conversation
chain.
So how this works is we can initialize a model again
and then start a conversation and then
we are going to call the dot predict method on the
conversation and provide it with an
input.
So right now the conversation is empty but we can
send this over and predict it and what
you can then see is that we will have a
conversation.
So there is a general prompt here so the following
is a friendly conversation between a human
and an AI.
The AI is talkative and provides lots of specific
details from its context etc.
So this is already engineered within the library and
then the human says hi there and then
the AI provides us with a response and that is the
output so we can print that and that
is hi there nice to meet you what can I do for you
and now what we can do next is we
have that output and we are going to make another
prediction by saying I'm doing well
just having a conversation with an AI.
So let's run this here you can see the history so
first we have the hi there then we have
the response from the AI and then you see our
response here again.
So what we've just entered and now we can print that
again and you can see that now
the AI is responding by it's great to be having a
conversation with you.
What would you like to talk about?
Alright and then next up is indexes so language
models are often more powerful when combined
with your own text data.
This module covers best practices for doing exactly
that.
So this is where it gets really exciting.
So this was the example that I was talking about
previously where you can build smart
applications for companies using their own data
their existing data and we will get more
into this in the example that I will provide at the
end of this video but for now just
know that there are document loaders text splitters
and vector stores and also retrievers.
So this is really exciting when we start to work
with our own data.
But for now let's continue to chains which is
another core component of the Lang chain
model so chains go beyond just a single large
language model call and our sequences of calls.
Lang chain provides a standard interface for chains
lots of integrations with other
tools and end to end chains for common applications.
So this is really where we start to bring things
together.
So the models and the prompts and the memory it's
nothing that new right.
We've seen it we can use it in chat GPT but now when
we start to chain things together
is when it gets really exciting.
So what does this look like in code?
So let's look at the LLM chain class that we can
import from Lang chain dot chains.
So given our previous model setup and the prompt
that we've provided so coming up with
a company name we can now actually start to run this
chain.
So the prompt template was just for engineering your
prompt.
The model is just for making a connection with the
API and now we can chain this together.
So let's quickly store this then set up this chain
so we provide the model and the prompt
as input parameters and now we can run this.
So let's try another example.
What is a good name for a company that makes AI chat
bots for dental offices AI DENTEC.
Love it.
All right so now you start to get a sense of how you
can turn this into an application.
You predefined the prompt over here and then you
combine it with user input and run that
using a chain.
So you could already turn this into a web app.
For example company name generator dot AI.
And now the trick here the key is being really smart
about what you put into these templates.
So this is a very straightforward example.
What is a good name for a company but you can get
really specific here and provide it
with lots of information really tailored to a
specific use case to get the result that
you are looking for given the user's input.
And I will give you a good example of this once we
start to develop the YouTube AI assistant
later in this video.
And then the last component agents.
So agents involve a large language model making
decisions about which actions to take taking
that action seeing an observation and repeating that
until it's done.
So this is really where you get to build your own
auto GPT baby AGI kind of applications
by using these agents and these agents can use
tools.
So there are tools agents toolkits and executors and
tools for example we have all kinds of
tools that are already supported straight out of the
box.
So we have Google searches we have Wikipedia we have
Google searches via the SERP API all
kinds of stuff that we can use.
And if we use these agents they will use the large
language model.
So for example the GPT model to assess which tool to
use and then use the tool to get the
information and then provide that back to the large
language model.
There is even a Pandas data frame agent that you can
use and it's mostly optimized for
question answering.
So here you can see a quick example and you can
basically ask it how many rows are there.
And then it knows that it can interact with the
Pandas data frame called the length function
to get the length of the data frame and then provide
that as a result.
So let's look at another example from the quick
start guide.
So if I want to start using agents what I can do is
I can import the initialized agent
type and the load tools to also provide it with some
tools.
And then coming back over here I can first list all
the tools.
So these are also on the website that was just
showing you in the documentation.
But here you can see the specific name that you have
to use in order to provide the agent
with that tool.
And now let's say for example we want to create an
agent and give it access to Wikipedia and
it should be able to do some math.
We can set up the tools like this then initialize
the agent provided with the tools the model
that is defined over here and then the agent type is
zero shot reacts description which
basically means that based on the prompt that we
give to the agent it will pick the best
tool to solve the problem.
So it will basically pick the tool on its own and
this is where it gets really interesting
because now you can provide an agent with a set of
tools and then it will figure out
on its own which tool to use to come up with the
best answer.
So let's try this query over here.
In what year was Python released and who's the
original creator multiply the year by
three and we only give it access to Wikipedia and
math.
All right.
So now let's first run this.
So let's see what it will do.
So new executor.
OK so it understands that it needs the action
Wikipedia and then you can see the input Python
programming language.
So it understands that that is the query that you
have to search for in Wikipedia.
Then it will get the history of Python summary.
So I have enough information to answer the question.
So the final answer Python was created in 1991 by
Gero van Rossem and the year multiplied
by three is five thousand seven hundred sixty three.
All right.
So this is really awesome right.
And this is beyond what chat GPT or the GPT models
are capable of because we can get live
information from the Internet.
And then also the results are stored as well.
So here you can just see the plain text string.
We now have that available.
And now if we start to combine everything together
so multiple chains multiple prompts
and then use agents to get information also use
memory to store everything.
Now we can actually build some really cool stuff.
All right.
So now I'm going to show you how you can create an
assistant that can answer questions about
the specific YouTube video.
So coming back to the indexes I've previously
explained how these large language models
become really powerful when you combine them with
your own data and your own data in this
scenario in this use case will be a YouTube
transcript that we are going to download
automatically.
But you can basically replace that transcript with
any other information and this approach
will still work.
So the chain library has document loaders text
splitters and vector stores and we are
going to use all of these.
So let's first talk about document loaders and these
are basically little helper tools
basically that make it easy to load certain
documents.
And here you can see everything that is supported
right now.
So we have things like Discord.
We have Figma.
We have Git.
We have Notion.
We have Obsidian PDFs PowerPoints but also YouTube.
So let's first see how we can get the YouTube
transcript given a video URL using this document
loader.
All right so coming back to VS Code we have the
following video URL over here which is
a podcast from the Lex Friedman podcast where he
talks to Sam Altman the CEO of OpenAI and
I thought this would be a nice video to use as an
example.
So we are going to first read the transcript of this
podcast this two and a half hour long
video using the document loader.
So for that we're going to import first the YouTube
loader from document loaders and we're
going to input the video URL.
So let's run this and see what we get.
So now we have the loader and to get the transcript
then we call the loader dot load method.
So we call this method over here and then run that
and then that will run for a while
and now we can have a look at the transcript over
here which is basically a very long string
over here with all the text in here.
All right so now we have the full transcript and it
is within a list and we can access
that using the page content to get the actual string
the actual transcript.
But now we have the following problem if I run this
to see how long the transcript is
we can see how many tokens there are in there.
So this is the total amount of characters and we can
see that it's over 100,000.
Now this was really a aha moment for me because you
cannot just provide this full transcript
with over 100,000 characters to the API of these
large language models.
It's just too large.
So if you want the model to be able to answer
questions about this transcript we have to
find a workaround to provide it with the information
it needs to answer the questions without sending
the transcript in full.
And that is where the text splitters come in because
if you go to the API documentation
you can see the max tokens over here per model for
OpenAI models.
And if you use the latest model that I can use right
now so the GPT 3.5 turbo it's 4096
tokens that you can input to the API.
If you're already on GPT-4 you can basically
increase the token size but for now we're
stuck to around 4000 tokens.
So how do we deal with that if we have a transcript
of over 100,000 tokens?
We can use the text splitter to first split this up
in several chunks.
So what this basically will do is I say hey we have
this transcript over here this size
but I want to split it up in chunk sizes of 1000
character each.
And here you can also specify if you want there to
be a bit of overlap.
And if I run this so let's run the text splitter and
then sorry first define the text splitter
and then call the text splitter split documents and
then put in the transcript that we've
just created.
So that is the object over here the list with the
document and the page content in here.
And if I run that so let's do that and now I now
have the docs and what we can now do
if we have a look at what docs is we can now see
that is just a list with a bunch of
split up documents.
So it has taken the very large transcript over
100,000 tokens and split it up into chunks
of 1000.
Okay so that is the first step.
Okay so now you might wonder okay so we've split up
the transcript but we can still not
provide it to the API right?
Correct and that is where the next part comes in and
that is embeddings and vector databases.
So this is quite technical and I won't go into the
details in this video I will make
future videos about this because for now I want to
give you a brief demonstration and
overview of how to use this and then later we can
get more specific.
But first we use the embeddings from OpenAI to
basically convert the text the splits that
we have just created of the 1000 tokens long to
convert them into vectors and vectors are
basically a in this case a numerical representation
of the text itself.
So we convert the text to a vector of numbers.
We will use the face library which is a library
developed by Facebook that you can use for
efficient similarity search.
We will combine that to basically create a database
of all these documents that you see
over here and when a user wants to ask a question
with regards to this YouTube transcript we
will first perform a similarity search to find the
chunks that are most similar to
the prompt that the user is asking.
So what this means is that we have this database
with all these vectors and we can do a similarity
search on that to find the relevant pieces of
information that we need and now this is
the critical key to working with these large
language models and your own data.
First create a filter a lookup table of some sort to
get just the information that you
want and then provide that to the large language
model with your question.
So if we bring all of that together in this function
create DB from YouTube video URL
we can for any given video URL load the transcript
then split it up into chunks of 1000 tokens
and then put it into a vector database object that
we can return using this function.
Now what we can then do next is we can provide this
to another function the get response
from query where we use this database that we've
just created to answer specific questions.
So how does this work?
Well we provide the database and the query so the
question you want to ask about the video
to this function get response from query and then we
also have a parameter k over here which
defaults to four and here you can see the reasoning
behind it but that is basically
to maximize the amount of tokens that we send to the
API and then this is where it gets really
interesting is we perform a similarity search on the
database using the query and we return k
documents.
So given our question it will go through all of
these documents and it will find the most similar
ones so it will do a similarity search and then what
we do once we have all the documents so four
by default we join them into one single string and
then we create a model over here and now we
use the GPT three and a half turbo model and next
you define a template for your prompt like we've
seen earlier in this video and this is where you can
get really creative so in this example you are
a helpful assistant that can answer questions about
youtube videos based on the video's transcript
and then we provide the input parameter docs which
we will replace by the string that we've
just created so all of the document information only
use factual information from the transcript
to answer the question if you feel like you don't
have enough information to answer the question
say i don't know your answer should be verbose and
details so like i've said this is really where
you can get creative and based on the kind of
applications that you want to create design your
template over here and basically by creating minor
changes within this template you can create
entirely different apps for all kinds of industries
all right and then the next step is to chain all
of this together and since we are now using the chat
function using the GPT three and a half turbo
model this is slightly different but you can find
everything in the quick start so first it explains
how you can use the general models and then it
continues with the chat models so the syntax is
a little different because here we have the system
message prompt and the human message prompt so this
is nice to first define a message a prompt for the
system basically so that is the description
over here the template explaining the AI the agent
basically what it should do and then we have a
prompt to alter the question or the input that the
human is providing so i for example edit answer
the following question and then put in the question
over here so i'm not sure if this is necessary
right now but you can alter the input from the user
as well so that is how you would do it and
then it combines all of that into a chat prompt and
then like we've seen earlier we can put that
into a chain the chat and the prompt and then we can
run that chain again also like we've seen
before and then we just put in a query and the docs
that we have defined earlier all right so now
we have all the building blocks that we need and we
can actually start to call these functions
so again let's define the video url and let's first
create a database from this video so let's
see what that will do so it goes quite quickly so it
gets the transcript and then converts it so now
we have the database object and now we can fill in a
query over here and then call the get response
from query function to answer a specific question
about this video transcript so let's actually see
what they are talking about and let's say i don't
have time to watch all of this but i'm pretty
interested in what they have to say about a gi over
here so i can come over here and listen to
what they have to say but i can now also come to
this application over here or this function so
to say and then fill in what are they saying about a
gi so that is the query and now let's get the
response and let's print it so there we go in the
video transcript they are discussing a gi
artificial general intelligence and the work being
done by open ai to develop it sam altman the ceo
and so on so it's answering the question based on
the transcript awesome so let's ask it another
question who are the hosts of this podcast so let's
run it all at once so it will do some thinking
first get the response and then based on the
transcript is not clear who the hosts of the
podcasts are however it is mentioned that the
podcast features conversations with guests such
as sam altman jordan peterson and is hosted by
someone named lax friedman okay so this is
really interesting it is admitting that it doesn't
have all the information but it is recognizing
all the entities and it is correct it's a podcast by
lax friedman all right so let's try another one
what are they saying about microsoft in the
transcript the speakers are discussing their
partnership with microsoft and how they have been
amazing partner to them all right awesome and now
also this function get response from query not only
returns the response but also the docs so
it's actually quite cool we can also have a look at
the documents for in this case that it's using
to get this answer so for this you also get the
reference to the original content which is very
convenient if you want to do additional research or
fact check your models to see if it's actually
giving you answers that are correct all right so now
we basically have a working app and all you
have to do is create a simple webpage around this
host it on a server or web app somewhere and people
can interact with this so fill in youtube url ask
questions and it will do that for you and really
when i look at all of this stuff my head really
starts to spin i have so many ideas because for
example what you can do with this approach alone
let's say you create a list of all the channels
that talk about a specific topic so for example you
want to stay up to date on ai you list all
the podcast channel all the popular channels and
then you create a little script that every now and
then checks if they have a new video public on their
page scrapes all the urls and then process
all of those videos with these functions and then
really engineer your prompt in such a way that you
can extract useful information from that that you
can use for example to do research or create a
social media account for example a twitter account
where you tweet about the latest updates in ai or
even a youtube channel where you want to talk about
ai you can really scout everything and then ask
okay what is the lex freedman postcards saying about
agi what is joe rogan saying about agi
and you can do that all automatically and then you
can combine this chaining it together with
different agents to store this information in files
on your you can see you can really the
possibilities are endless so like i've said i am
really going to dive deep into this because there
are so many opportunities right now and as i will
learn i will keep you guys up to date on my youtube
channel so if you're interested in this make sure to
subscribe so you don't miss any future videos
on this and really it's been amazing how many
requests i'm already getting from companies to
help them implement these tools help them with ai
i've been getting tons of messages so it's
really exciting so for me as a freelancer this is a
really exciting opportunity a really exciting
moment to basically also start to work with smaller
clients smaller companies and implement
these tools and now if you also feel like you want
to do more with this you want to exploit
this opportunity and start to work on your own
freelance projects but don't really know
where to start then you should really check out data
freelancer which is a mastermind that i
host specifically created for data professionals
that want to kickstart launch their freelance
career in data but don't really know where to start
so in this mastermind you will literally
learn everything you need to get started to start
landing your first paid projects i share
all my systems and models that i've developed over
the years to basically systemize freelancing in
data to make sure you never run out of clients and
you will become part of a community of other data
professionals that are working on their freelancing
career and we are all here together to work on the
same goals of making more money working on fun
projects and creating freedom that's what we're
trying to do here feels like hanging out with
friends but with real business results so if
you consider freelancing or want to take advantage
of all the amazing opportunities that are out there
right now in the world of ai but don't really know
where to start then check out data freelancer
first link in the description and sign up for the
wait list